Register of the Max Marawske Collection, 1890-1918
Hoover Institution Archives
Max Marawske Collection,
1890-1918
XX246
Marawske, Max, collector
40 manuscript boxes (16.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings from German newspapers and periodicals, relating to World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Germany.; Germany.
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1890-1918 (Box 1-40)
  Newspaper clippings from German newspapers and periodicals, printed photos, and other printed matter, relating to aspects of World War I and collected by Max Marawske, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American Indians (Box 1.)
  - American Negroes
  - Augusta Victoria, Empress of Germany
  - Countries and continents
    - Afghanistan
    - Africa
    - Albania
    - Algeria
    - Alsace-Lorraine
    - Angola
    - Annam
    - Arabia
    - Argentina
    - Asia
    - Australia
    - Austria-Hungary (Box 2.)
      - Budapest
      - General
      - General (Box 3.)
      - History
    - Balkan States
    - Bavaria (Box 4.)
      - Geography
      - General
      - History
      - History (Box 5.)
      - Munich
    - Belgium
    - Borneo
    - Brazil
    - Bulgaria
    - Burma
    - Cambodia
    - Canada
      - General
      - Newfoundland
      - Ontario
    - Canary Islands
    - Ceylon (Sri Lanka)
    - Chile
    - China (Box 6.)
      - General
      - Peking
    - Colombia
    - Congo
    - Denmark
      - General
      - Bornholm
      - Copenhagen
    - Dutch East Indies
    - Egypt
    - England
      - Cities
      - General
    - Ethiopia
    - Europe (Box 7.)
    - Ferdinand Islands
    - Finland
    - France
      - Cities
      - General (Box 8.)
    - French Sudan
    - French West Africa
    - Germany
      - German cities and principalities
        - General
        - Anhalt
        - Baden
        - Braunschweig
        - Bremen
        - East Prussia
        - Hamburg
        - Hannover (Box 9.)
        - Leipzig
        - Lübeck
        - Lüneburg
        - Mecklenburg
        - North Sea
        - Oldenburg
        - Pomerania
        - Rhineland (Box 10.)
        - Rhineland Valley Provinces
        - Schleswig-Holstein (Box 11.)
        - Schwanberg-Lippe
        - Silesia
        - Thüringen
        - Waldeck (Box 12.)
        - Wartburg
        - Westphalia
        - West Prussia
      - German colonies
        - General
        - Cameroon
        - German Congo
        - German East Africa
        - German South Africa
        - German West Africa
        - Gold Coast
        - Somoa
        - Togo
    - Greece
    - Greenland
    - Guatemala
    - India (Box 13.)
    - Iraq
    - Ireland
    - Italy
      - General
      - Rome (Box 14.)
      - Venice
    - Japan
    - Korea
    - Lichtenstein
    - Luxemburg
    - Lybia
    - Madagascar
    - Madeira
    - Malaysian Archipelago
    - Malta
    - Mexico
    - Monaco
    - Morocco (Box 15.)
    - Netherlands
    - Neutral Moresnet
    - Nigeria
    - North Pole
    - Norway, Cities
    - Oceania (The Celebes, Fanning Islands, Fiji, Java, Sumatra) (Box 16.)
    - Paraguay
    - Persia
    - Peru
    - Philippines
    - Poland
    - Portugal
    - Prussia
      - General
      - Geographical
      - Provinces
    - Romania (Box 17.)
    - Russia
      - General
      - Provinces
    - Saint Helena
    - Senegal
    - Serbia
    - South Africa
    - South Pole (Box 18.)
    - Spain
      - Cities
      - General
    - Spanish Guinea
    - Sudan
    - Sweden
    - Switzerland
    - Switzerland (Box 19.)
    - Thailand
    - Tibet
    - Tunisia
    - Turkey
    - United States
      - General
      - Alaska (Box 20.)
      - California, San Francisco
      - Colorado
      - Illinois, Chicago
      - Kansas
      - Michigan
      - Minnesota
      - Missouri, St. Louis
      - New York
        - New York City
        - Buffalo
      - South Carolina
      - South Dakota
      - Utah, Salt Lake City
      - Vermont
      - Wisconsin
      - Wyoming
    - Uruguay
    - Vatican
    - Venezuela
    - Württemberg
    - Yugoslavia
  - Franz-Joseph I, Emperor of Austria, King of Hungary, 1830-1916
  - French Foreign Legion
  - Hindenburg, Otto von
  - Islam
  - Ludendorff, Erich
  - Ludwig I, King of Bavaria, 1786-1868
  - Ludwig II, King of Bavaria, 1845-1886
  - Ludwig III, King of Bavaria, 1845-1921 (Box 21.)
  - Otto I, King of Bavaria, 1848-1916
  - Rupprecht, Crown Prince of Bavaria, 1869-1955
  - Vikings and Viking ships
  - Volcanos
    - Mt. Etna, Sicily
    - Mt. Vesuvius, Italy
  - Wilhelm, Crown Prince of Germany
  - Wilhelm II, Emperor of Germany, King of Prussia, 1859-1941
  - World War I
    - Africa
    - Albania
    - Alsace-Lorraine
    - Arabia
    - Asia
    - Austria-Hungary (Box 22.)
    - Balkans, The
    - Bavaria
    - Belgium (Box 23.)
    - Bismarck, Prince Otto von
    - Bulgaria
    - Caribbean
    - Central Africa
    - China
    - Denmark
    - Dutch East Indies
    - Egypt
    - England (Box 24.)
    - Finland
    - France
      - General
      - General (Box 25.)
      - Officers
    - French Guinea (Box 26.)
    - Frederick the Great, King of Prussia, 1712-1786
    - Germany
      - Animals
      - Army
      - Artillery
      - Authors
      - Aviation
      - Aviation (Box 27.)
      - Captured territory
      - Catholic Church
      - Cities and provinces
        - Berlin
        - Bremen (Box 28.)
        - Hamburg
        - Hannover
        - East Prussia
        - Schleswig-Holstein
      - Civil servants
      - Colonies
      - Diplomacy
      - Fatalities
      - Heroes
      - Holidays (Box 29.)
      - Intelligentsia
      - Illustrations
      - Iron Cross
      - Literature
      - Mail (Box 30.)
      - Military operations
      - Ministry
      - Music
      - Naval operations (Box 31.)
      - Officers (Box 32.)
      - Preparation for war
      - Princes
      - Prisoners of war
      - Railroad
      - Repairs
      - Women (Box 33.)
      - Youth
    - Greece
    - Hindenburg, Paul von
    - Hohenzollern princes
    - India
    - Italy
    - Japan
    - Luxemburg (Box 34.)
    - Lybia
    - Mackensen, August von
    - Mexico
    - Morocco
    - Monaco
    - Montenegro
    - Netherlands
    - North Africa
    - Norway
    - Newspaper clippings from World War I
    - Newspaper clippings from World War I (Box 35-36.)
    - Oceania (Box 37.)
    - Persia
    - Poland
    - Portugal
    - Prisoners of war
    - Prussia
    - Red Cross
    - Romania
    - Russia (Box 38.)
    - San Marino
    - Serbia
    - Silesia
    - South America (Box 39.)
    - Spain
    - Sweden
    - Switzerland
    - Trench warfare
    - Turkey
    - United States (Box 40.)
    - Vatican
    - World War I - aftermath